<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methods on r-econometrics</title>
    <link>https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methods on r-econometrics</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Standard Test Statistics for OLS Models in R</title>
      <link>https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/teststats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/teststats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Model testing belongs to the main tasks of any econometric analysis. This post gives an overview of tests, which should be applied to OLS regressions, and illustrates how to calculate them in R. The focus of the post is rather on the calcuation of the tests. For a treatment of mathematical details, please, consult a standard textbook. This list of statistical tests is necessarily incomplete. However, if you have a strong opinion that a specific test is missing, feel free to leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteroskedasticity Robust Standard Errors in R</title>
      <link>https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/hcrobusterrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/hcrobusterrors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although heteroskedasticity does not produce biased &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/ols&#34;&gt;OLS&lt;/a&gt; estimates, it leads to a bias in the variance-covariance matrix. This means that standard model testing methods such as t tests or F tests cannot be relied on any longer. This post provides an intuitive illustration of heteroskedasticity and covers the calculation of standard errors that are robust to it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div id=&#34;data&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A popular illustration of heteroskedasticity is the relationship between saving and income, which is shown in the following graph. The dataset is contained the &lt;em&gt;wooldridge&lt;/em&gt; package.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Ordinary Least Squares (OLS) in R</title>
      <link>https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/ols/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.r-econometrics.com/methods/ols/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Formulated at the beginning of the 19th century by Legendre and Gauss the method of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Least_squares&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;least squares&lt;/a&gt; is a standard tool in econometrics to assess the relationships between different variables. This site gives a short introduction to the basic idea behind the method and describes how to estimate simple linear models with OLS in R.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div id=&#34;the-method-of-least-squares&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;The method of least squares&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand the basic idea of the method of least squares, imagine you were an astronomer at the beginning of the 19th century, who faced the challenge of combining a series of observations, which were made with imperfect instruments and at different points in time.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; One day you draw a scatter plot, which looks similar to the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
